The imagination behind Wuthering Heights.
Emily is a history, drama, romance film directed by Frances O'Connor.
The imagined life of one of the world’s most famous authors, Emily Brontë, as she
finds her voice and writes the literary classic Wuthering Heights.
Explore the relationships that inspired her – her raw, passionate sisterhood with Charlotte and Anne; her first
aching, forbidden love for Weightman and her care for her maverick brother whom she idolises.
Emily Brontë, played by Emma Mackey.
Branwell Brontë, played by Fionn Whitehead.
William Weightman, played by Oliver Jackson-Cohen.
Charlotte Brontë, played by Alexandra Dowling.
Aunt Branwell, played by Gemma Jones.
Patrick Brontë, played by Adrian Dunbar.
Emily is a 2022 British biographical drama film written and
directed by Frances O'Connor in her directorial debut.
It is a part-fictional portrait of English writer Emily Brontë (played by Emma Mackey),
concentrating on a fictional romantic relationship with the young curate William Weightman.
Fionn Whitehead, Oliver Jackson-Cohen, Alexandra Dowling, Amelia Gething,
Adrian Dunbar and Gemma Jones appear in supporting roles.
Emily premiered at the 2022 Toronto International Film Festival before being
theatrically released in the United Kingdom by Warner Bros.
Pictures on 14 October 2022.
The film explores themes of england, author, woman
director, deathbed, fictional biography.
The tone is emotional.